<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<question id="6.1" module="IPP">
   <questionText>What are the objectives of IPv6? Please state at least 4 objectives.
</questionText>
   <referenceAnswers>
     <referenceAnswer id="IPP_6.1_a1">To support billions of end-systems.
To reduce routing tables.
To simplify protocol processing with Simplified header.
To increase security.
To support real time data traffic (quality of service).
Flow label, traffic class.
To provide multicasting.
To support mobility (roaming).
To be open for change (future): extension headers for additional change incorporation.
To coexistence with existing protocols.

</referenceAnswer>
   </referenceAnswers>
   <studentAnswers><studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.7"> 
	 <response>1: More addresses. Support for billions of end-systems, so that every end-systen can have its own IP Address.
2:Simplifying protocol processing by simplifying the headers.
3: To provide multicasting without the need for additional systems. 
4: Flexibility in use, by enabling extension headers. 
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>All four IPv6 objectives mentioned in the response are completely accurate.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.13"> 
	 <response> 1.) Global addressing concept for end systems
2.) Simplified address allocation
3.) Addresses independent from
  - type and topology of the subnetworks
  - number and type of the subnetworks to which the end systems have been connected 
  - location of a source end systems
4.) Increasing data security
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response correctly answers four objectives of IPv6.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.15"> 
	 <response>- extend the space of possible host addresses compared to IPv4
- simplify the protocol packages by removing unused header entries
- provide better support for multicast and anycast
- to allow flexibility for future changes (e.g. with extension headers)
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response is correct because all stated objectives of IPv 6 are correct.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.28"> 
	 <response>no response
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response is empty.</response_feedback>
     <score>0</score>
	<verification_feedback>Incorrect</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.32"> 
	 <response> - Support billions of end-systems by using longer addresses
- Coexistence with existing protocols
- Support roaming
- Reduce routing tables
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response is correct as it contains accurate IPv6 objectives.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.38"> 
	 <response> - Support larger number of end systems than IPv4 by using longer addresses
- Reduce size of routing tables
- Simplify protocol processing by simplifying header
- Improve multicast support
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>All four objectives of IPv6 are completely accurate.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.45"> 
	 <response> IPv6 is made for supporting more addresses allowing billions of end-systems. It also gives the possibility to increase security and to simplify protocol processing. Additional IPv6 provides multicasting beneath a few other objectives.
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response contains four correct objectives of IPv6.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.54"> 
	 <response>1. Enlarge the available address pool:
    By increasing the IP address length from 32 bits to 128 bits, a greater number of addresses can be assigned to end systems.
2. Simplify protocol processing:
    Any previous shortcomings in IPv4 can be removed and optimized in IPv6.
3. Provide Multicasting:
    Packets can now be sent to multiple destination addresses, which makes multicasting possible.
4. Better Security:
    Security means are already integrated in IPv6.

	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response correctly states four objectives of IPv6 with explanations.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.60"> 
	 <response>No response 
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response is empty.</response_feedback>
     <score>0</score>
	<verification_feedback>Incorrect</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.61"> 
	 <response> 
 -support billions of end-systems (with specific addresses) 
-reduce routing tables
-simplify protocol processing 
-increase security
-support real time data traffic (QoS)
-support mobility
-be open for change in future with extension headers

	 </response>
     <response_feedback>All the IPv6 objectives mentioned in the answer are completely accurate.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.69"> 
	 <response> - Support more end-systems by using much longer addresses than IPv4
- Simplify protocol processing by using a less complex header (especially no more checksum in header which must recalculated after each hop)
- Provide multicast and anycast
- Usage of extension headers to be open for future changes/extensions
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response is correct as it correctly answers four objectives of IPv6.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.72"> 
	 <response> Longer Addresses - IPv6 adresses in 2^(128) Bits instead like in IPv4. This fact allows us to address much more devices.
To increase security - because IPv6 allow to connect specified devices all over the world, ipv6 needed to support native end to end encryption.
To reduce routing tables - by simplifing Header. i.e by taking out header checksum , because L2 and L4 already have sufficend mechanisms.
To be open for change - Header can be changend or added to extend ipv6.
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response is correct because all stated objectives and explanations are correct.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.75"> 
	 <response> -Provide more adresses
-simplify protocol processing
-be usable while IPv4 is still in use
-increase security
	 </response>
     <response_feedback>All four IPv6 objectives mentioned in the response are completely correct.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	<studentAnswer id="IPP_6.1.76"> 
	 <response> 1. Enlarge the available address pool:
    By increasing the IP address length from 32 bits to 128 bits, a greater number of addresses can be assigned to end systems.
2. Simplify protocol processing:
    Any previous shortcomings in IPv4 can be removed and optimized in IPv6.
3. Provide Multicasting:
    Packets can now be sent to multiple destination addresses, which makes multicasting possible.
4. Better Security:
    Security means are already integrated in IPv6.

	 </response>
     <response_feedback>The response correctly states four objectives of IPv6 with explanations.</response_feedback>
     <score>1</score>
	<verification_feedback>Correct</verification_feedback></studentAnswer>
	</studentAnswers></question>